<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Promises &#8211; Promises Treatment Centre</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Where Hope in Life is Rekindled</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 11:51:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Facts about Drug Addiction</title>
		<link>./../../../facts-about-drug-addiction/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Promises]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 13:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ricupero/?p=493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How the Brain Works The brain is composed of millions of interconnecting nerve cells, called neurons. In order for the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>How the Brain Works</em><br>
The brain is composed of millions of interconnecting nerve cells, called neurons. In order for the brain to function so that a person can think, move, or feel, these neurons must communicate. They do so by receiving, processing, and sending chemical signals called neurotransmitters. When a neurotransmitter is released from one neuron it binds to another at a specific site called a receptor, much like the way a key fits into a lock. If the key fits, the receiving neuron will be able to process the signal and send it on.<br>
<em>Physical Effects of Drug Use</em><br>
A drug is any substance that, once inside the body, changes how the body works. Drugs can be swallowed, sniffed, inhaled, injected, absorbed through the skin, or dropped into the eye. No matter the route of administration, most drugs will eventually travel through the circulatory system and reach the brain. </p>



<p>In the brain, drugs can affect almost any step in the communication between neurons by increasing or decreasing the amount of neurotransmitter that reaches the receiving neuron. A drug can also bind directly to a receptor in place of a neurotransmitter. In the case of drug abuse, the interference in nerve communication often causes a temporary pleasurable sensation.<br>
<em>What Is Drug Addiction?</em><br>
With drug addiction, a person craves the pleasurable sensation produced by a drug and compulsively uses it despite its negative consequences. </p>



<p>The use of certain kinds of drugs may also produce a physical addiction or dependence, meaning that the drug must be present for the body to function normally. In this case, when the drug is withdrawn, the user may experience mild to severe effects ranging from nausea to death.<br>
<em>Treatment for Drug Addiction</em><br>
There are many ways to treat a person with drug addiction, and a physician-supervised program is the most appropriate and safe type of management.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alcoholism Warning Signs</title>
		<link>./../../../alcoholism-warning-signs/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Promises]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 14:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.athemes.com/atu-health-coach/?p=286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Regardless of the number of warning signs, alcoholism symptoms are real and recognizable. To the alcoholic in denial, however, they [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Regardless of the number of warning signs, alcoholism symptoms are real and recognizable. To the alcoholic in denial, however, they are not so recognizable.<br />
I believe that most alcoholics, in a certain sense, CHOOSE to be in a state of denial even in the face of clear alcoholism symptoms. They know these things about themselves. Or at the very least, someone close to them has told them these things.</p>
<p>Here are some of the warning signs:<br />
* Drinking more than you used to.<br />
* Drinking alone.<br />
* Drinking more than your friends and wanting to drink longer than your friends.<br />
* A high toleration for alcohol; needing more and more to get that buzz.<br />
* Lying about the amount of alcohol you consume.<br />
* Drinking first thing in the morning.<br />
* Blackouts.<br />
* Legal problems or accidents related to alcohol &#8211; things like car accidents, DUI’s, falls, fist fights, domestic violence, financial problems, etc.<br />
* Problems in relationships with loved ones. Criticism about your drinking from people who know you best.<br />
* Odors of alcohol when around individual, especially on breath.<br />
* Shakes, delirium tremens.<br />
* Increase or decrease in weight.<br />
* Repeated complaints of fatigue, lack of energy, inability to concentrate, headaches, etc.<br />
* Unpredictability, strange behavior.<br />
* Withdrawal from responsibility.<br />
* Loses touch with reality at times.<br />
* Loss of mental sharpness, creativity, business acumen.<br />
* Chronic lateness.<br />
* Trouble making rational decisions.<br />
* Quality of work/dressing deteriorates.</p>
<p>Among others.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Am I an Alcoholic?</title>
		<link>./../../../am-i-an-alcoholic/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Promises]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 14:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.athemes.com/atu-health-coach/?p=287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There has been some confusion about what alcoholism is. Many people mistakenly assume that being an alcoholic is based on [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There has been some confusion about what alcoholism is. Many people mistakenly assume that being an alcoholic is based on how many drinks they consume, but like any other disease, there are varying stages and levels.<br />
According to James E. Royce, S.J., Ph.D., and David Scratchley, Ph.D., alcoholism can be defined as “a chronic primary illness or disorder characterized by some loss of control over drinking, with habituation or addiction to the drug alcohol, or causing interference in any major life function, for example: health, job, family, friends, legal or spiritual.”</p>
<p><strong>Loss of Control</strong><br />
Most alcoholics can take a few drinks without getting drunk, but that does not mean they don’t have a drinking problem. Total loss of control is typically seen in late-stage alcoholics, but a consistent loss of control can be sufficient for diagnosis. The loss of control can be in regard to how much they drink or when they drink, or both. Also, drinking more than intended or drinking at inappropriate times can be sufficient for diagnosis.</p>
<p><strong>Dependence</strong><br />
Chemical dependence can be either psychological or physiological. Psychological dependence typically refers to those who feel discomfort without alcohol even though there is no physical need. Physiological dependence is characterized by increased tolerance, brain changes and withdrawal symptoms. At this stage, people physically need to drink in order to function.</p>
<p><strong>Interference</strong><br />
Another factor in defining alcoholism is whether alcohol interferes with an individual’s normal life. Interference is much more subjective and difficult to quantify, but the interference must be habitual and notable. For instance, if alcohol use results in one argument, that may not be considered interference, but all-out bar brawls are a common and recurring situation, then that would be construed as interference. Just as one DUI may be considered an anomaly, three consecutive DUIs are grounds for arrest and therefore constitute interference.<br />
If any of these descriptions apply to you, it’s time to get help. There are a number of effective treatments for alcoholism, including outpatient programs, residential alcohol addiction treatment and therapy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self Diagnosis Denial</title>
		<link>./../../../self-diagnosis-denial/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Promises]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 14:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://demo.athemes.com/atu-health-coach/?p=284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What do you think and say to yourself about using alcohol and other drugs? Check off any statements you have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What do you think and say to yourself about using alcohol and other drugs? Check off any statements you have made to others or thought to yourself.</p>
<p>*(A)*<br />
___________I don’t have a problem<br />
___________I can handle it<br />
___________I’m not hooked – I can quit any time I want<br />
___________Leave me alone – it’s my business<br />
___________I’m not hurting anyone but myself<br />
___________So what?<br />
___________(Other)</p>
<p>*(B)*<br />
___________Sure I drink (Smoke, snort etc) but it’s not a problem<br />
___________It was just a little dent in the car. At least I didn’t hurt anyone<br />
___________It’s not a big deal<br />
___________A least I didn’t behave as bad as______________<br />
___________I made it home all right. Everything must have been okay<br />
___________It will be all right if I just apologize and cool it for a while<br />
___________(Other)</p>
<p>*(C)*<br />
___________It is not the booze (coke, pills, etc) it’s the stress (coffee, cigarettes, ___________allergies, medication, etc)<br />
___________It wasn’t my fault – it was (_______ __________’s) fault for getting me drunk<br />
___________I need it because of my bad (nerve, children etc)<br />
___________My wife (husband, wife, kid etc) drive me to do it<br />
___________I would have been alright if I hadn’t mixed drinks (drank on an empty                                  .                     stomach, been sold coke cut with speed<br />
___________(Other)</p>
<p>*(D)*<br />
___________I’m self medicating. It helps me relax (cope with pain, digest, etc)<br />
___________It’s been a day that would drive anyone to drink<br />
___________I got carried away because I was so happy (sad, mad, upset, nervous, etc)<br />
___________Everyone makes mistakes once in a while<br />
___________I’ll just have one drink (shot, etc) to steady my nerves<br />
___________(Other)</p>
<p>*(E)*<br />
___________A night cap will help me sleep. If I get a good night sleep, I won’t feel such .                     a strong need to drink tomorrow<br />
___________I need the hair of the dog that bit me<br />
___________Its hot (cold, rainy, nice, etc) lets have one<br />
___________I’m already loaded. One more won’t make a difference<br />
___________I’ll quit tomorrow<br />
___________(Other)</p>
<p>*(F)*<br />
___________Alcohol and drugs aren’t the cause of my problems. They’re just a      .                    .                     symptom of my crazy life<br />
___________I don’t know why I have this strange pain (when you know it’s probably an .                     ulcer or liver damage caused by alcohol)<br />
___________We need more fibber in our diet (when you know your diarrhea and                     .                     constipation are caused by drinking)<br />
___________My allergies are awful today (when you have the coke sniffles)<br />
___________You’d drink too if you lived my life. Let me tell you about…<br />
___________(Other)</p>
<p>*(G)*<br />
___________You’ve got a lot of nerve talking about my drinking<br />
___________Get off my back<br />
___________As soon as I unwind a little you’re breathing down my neck<br />
___________You’re just like my mother – nag, nag, and nag.<br />
___________I’ll stop doping (drinking, smoking, etc) when you stop throwing money         .                     away. (Get a job, stop crying all the time, stop cheating on me, etc)<br />
___________Why don’t you clean up this dump instead of counting my drinks?<br />
___________Oh yeah? And who wrecked the car (ran over his own dog, set the mattress .                     on fire, etc)<br />
___________(Other)</p>
<p>Men and women drink because they like the effects produced by alcohol. The sensation is so elusive that, while they admit it’s injurious, they cannot after a time differentiate the true from the false. To them, the alcoholic life seems the only normal one.</p>
<p>All alcoholics have one thing in common: they cannot start drinking without developing the phenomenon of craving. This phenomenon as we have suggested, may be the manifestation of an allergy which differentiates these people, and sets them apart as a distinct entity. It has never been, by any treatment by which we are familiar, permanently eradicated. The only relief we have to suggest is entire abstinence.<br />
/(Alcoholics Anonymous, pg xxiii, xxiv)/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
